JESWIN VARKEY GEORGE

Data Analyst, <u>Tableau Desktop Specialist</u>
Pune, Maharashtra, India | +91 8129737357 | <u>jeswinvgeorge22@gmail.com</u>
<u>LinkedIn profile</u> | <u>GitHub profile</u> | <u>Tableau public profile</u> | <u>My Website</u>

Objective

Data analyst with 2+ years of experience in the information technology and retail services industry. Excels at data wrangling, data mining and making dashboards using Python, R and Tableau. Seeking to apply my abilities to fill the Data Analyst role in your company.

Technologies

LANGUAGES: Python
DATABASES: PostgreSQL
TOOLS: Tableau, R, MS Excel
CLOUD: Microsoft Azure

Professional Experience

Infosys (Analytics unit), Pune, Senior Associate Analyst

Feb 2018-Present

➤ **Project:** Migrating a predictive model engine from Cloudera to MS Azure

Project duration: January 2020 – Present

Team strength: 3

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Creating connection between azure data lake and clusters.
- Testing the different cases of data sanity check.
- **Project:** Creating a baseline demand forecasting model for a retail giant.

Project duration: September 2019 – December 2019

Team strength: 3

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Assigned as data wrangler of the team.
- Scrapped websites to extract required data using Python (Beautiful soup).
- Cleaning and organising the unstructured data to tidy format using Python (Pandas).
- Applied EDA to get insights about the data using Python and Tableau.
- Created dashboards using Tableau for presentation to the client and higher management.
- Achieved accuracy of 90%.

➤ **Project:** PLM Data Migration for a retail client **Project duration:** July 2018 – August 2019

Team strength: 55 (Overall 5 teams) **Responsibilities and achievements:**

- Teams: Data mining, Data matching, Data remediation, UI/BI and testing teams.
- Part of the Data matching engine creation team.
- Flagging the inconsistencies among the data from different ERPs using R, MS Excel and PostgreSQL.
- Unit testing and system testing of the developed matching engine.
- Ensure quick response to the issues raised by other teams or final application user.
- Analysing the impact of change request and logged defects at process level and project level.
- Created reports and dashboards using excel and R-shiny to present the results to the stakeholders.
- Mentoring new members joining the team and guiding them to get accustomed to the project environment.
- Achieved matching accuracy of 99.5%.

Udacity, Classroom Mentor

Dec 2017-Feb 2018

- Mentored students pursuing Udacity's Data Analyst Nanodegree program.
- Encouraged and guided 20 students assigned to me.

Side Projects

Identify Fraud from Enron Email

Link to project

• Applied machine learning to identify the fraud in the Enron scandal.

Wrangle Open Street Map Data

Link to project

• Wrangled Open street map data of New Delhi, India using Python.

Test a perceptual phenomenon – Stroop Effect

Link to project

• Applied inferential statistics on a test conducted on the Stroop effect.

EDA of red wine dataset

Link to project

 Applied exploratory data analysis techniques to get insights about the red wines dataset.

Scrapping website for hotels and their prices

Link to project

• Scrapped Goibibo website for hotels in Pune.

Tableau public profile

Link to project

• Collection of vizzes made by me in Tableau.

Education

Coursera, Data Visualization and Communication with Tableau	Sept 2018 - Nov 2018
Udacity, Data Analyst Nanodegree	June 2017 - Dec 2017
SRM University, MTech Communication Systems	July 2015 - May 2017
University of Calicut, BTech ECE	June 2010 - May 2014